The first feature representation we'll look at is called Bag of Words.
我们学习的第一个特征表示法称为词袋
The Bag of Words model treats each document as an un-ordered collection or bag of words.
词袋模型将每个文档看作无序的词集合或词袋
Here, a document is the unit of text that you want to analyze.
在这里 文档就是你要分析的文本单位
For instance, if you want to compare essays
例如 如果你想比较学生提交的论文
submitted by students to check for plagiarism,
检查是否有抄袭行为
each essay would be a document.
那么每篇论文就是一个文档
If you want to analyze the sentiment conveyed by tweets,
如果你想分析推文传达的感情
then each tweet would be a document.
那么每个推文就是一个文档
To obtain a bag of words from a piece of raw text,
要从一段原始文本获取词袋
you need to simply apply appropriate text processing steps: cleaning,
只需要进行合适的文本处理步骤 清洗
normalizing, splitting into words,
标准化 分词
stemming, lemmatization, et cetera.
词干提取 词形还原等
And then treat the resulting tokens as an un-ordered collection or set.
然后将生成的词条作为无序的集合
So, each document in your data set will produce a set of words.
因此 数据集中的每个文档都会生成一个词集
But keeping these as separate sets is very inefficient.
但是将其保持为单独的集合是无用处的
They're of different sizes,
它们的大小不同
may contain different words,
包含的词可能不同
and are hard to compare.
而且难以比较
Also, whatever word occurs multiple times in a document?
另外 如果一个词在一个文档中出现多次呢？
Is there a better representation you can think of?
你能想出更好的表示法吗？
A more useful approach is to turn each document into a vector of numbers,
一个更有效的方法是将每个文档转换成数字向量
representing how many times each word occurs in a document.
数字向量表示的是每个词在一个文档中出现的次数
A set of documents is known as a corpus,
一组文档就是一个语料库
and this gives the context for the vectors to be calculated.
这为要计算的向量提供了上下文
First, collect all the unique words present in your corpus to form your vocabulary.
首先 将语料库中出现的所有唯一词提取出来 形成词汇表
Arrange these words in some order,
按某种顺序排列这些词
and let them form the vector element positions or columns of a table,
使其形成向量元素位置或表格的列
and assume each document is a row.
假设每个文档是一行
Then count the number of occurrences of each word in
然后统计每个词在每个文档中出现的次数
each document and enter the value in the respective column.
将值输入各个列
At this stage, it is easier to think of this as a Document-Term Matrix,
在这一阶段 为了方便起见 可以将其作为一个文档-词条矩阵
illustrating the relationship between documents in rows,
行是文档 列是词或词条
and words or terms in columns.
它呈现了文档与词条之间的关系
Each element can be interpreted as a term frequency.
可以将每个元素理解成词频
How frequently does that term occur in this document?
也就是这个词条在该文档中出现的频率
Now, consider what you can do with this representation.
现在思考一下如何使用这个表示法
One possibility is to compare two documents based on
一种方法是比较两个文档中
how many words they have in common or how similar their term frequencies are.
有多少共有词 或者词频的相似度有多高
A more mathematical way of expressing that is to
一个偏数学专业的表示方法是
compute the dot product between the two row vectors,
计算两个行向量之间的点积
which is the sum of the products of corresponding elements.
也就是对应元素积的总和
Greater the dot product,
点积越大
more similar the two vectors are.
两个向量的相似度越高
The dot product has one flaw,
点积有一个缺陷
it only captures the portions of overlap.
只能捕捉重叠部分
It is not affected by other values that are not uncommon.
它不受其它不同值的影响
So, pairs that are very different can end up
因此 差别很大的两个行
with the same product as ones that are identical.
和差别相同的两个行 其点积可能相等
A better measure is cosine similarity,
更好的方法是计算余弦相似度
where we divide the dot product of two vectors by
也就是将两个向量的点积除以
the product of their magnitudes or Euclidean norms.
其量值的积或欧几里得范数
If you think of these vectors as arrows in some n-dimensional space,
如果将这些向量作为 n 维空间中的箭头
then this is equal to the cosine of the angle theta between them.
则等于两者之间的角 θ 的余弦值
Identical vectors have cosine equals one.
相等向量的余弦值等于 1
Orthogonal vectors have cosine equal zero.
正交向量的余弦值等于 0
And for vectors that are exactly opposite, it is minus one.
对于完全相反的向量 其余弦值为 -1
So, the values always range nicely between one for most similar,
因此 余弦值始终在 1 与 -1 之间
to minus one, most dissimilar.
1 表示相似度最高 -1 表示相似度最低